<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>News - Category - π4h Lab</title>
        <link>https://www.joshuachou.ink/categories/news/</link>
        <description>News - Category - π4h Lab</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.joshuachou.ink/categories/news/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>[NEWS] A recent project: SkinGPT-4: An Interactive Dermatology Diagnostic System with Visual Large Language Model</title>
    <link>https://www.joshuachou.ink/news-skingpt-4/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.joshuachou.ink/news-skingpt-4/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce the SkinGPT-4: An Interactive Dermatology Diagnostic System with Visual Large Language Model</p>
<p>Skin and subcutaneous diseases rank high among the leading contributors to the global burden of nonfatal diseases, impacting a considerable portion of the population. Nonetheless, the field of dermatology diagnosis faces three significant hurdles. Firstly, there is a shortage of dermatologists accessible to diagnose patients, particularly in rural regions. Secondly, accurately interpreting skin disease images poses a considerable challenge. Lastly, generating patient-friendly diagnostic reports is usually a time-consuming and labor-intensive task for dermatologists. To tackle these challenges, we present SkinGPT-4, which is the world&rsquo;s first interactive dermatology diagnostic system powered by an advanced visual large language model. SkinGPT-4 leverages a fine-tuned version of MiniGPT-4, trained on an extensive collection of skin disease images (comprising 52,929 publicly available and proprietary images) along with clinical concepts and doctors&rsquo; notes. We designed a two-step training process to allow SkinGPT-4 to express medical features in skin disease images with natural language and make accurate diagnoses of the types of skin diseases. With SkinGPT-4, users could upload their own skin photos for diagnosis, and the system could autonomously evaluate the images, identifies the characteristics and categories of the skin conditions, performs in-depth analysis, and provides interactive treatment recommendations. Meanwhile, SkinGPT-4&rsquo;s local deployment capability and commitment to user privacy also render it an appealing choice for patients in search of a dependable and precise diagnosis of their skin ailments. To demonstrate the robustness of SkinGPT-4, we conducted quantitative evaluations on 150 real-life cases, which were independently reviewed by certified dermatologists, and showed that SkinGPT-4 could provide accurate diagnoses of skin diseases. Though SkinGPT-4 is not a substitute for doctors, it could enhance users&rsquo; comprehension of their medical conditions, facilitate improve communication between patients and doctors, expedite the diagnostic process for dermatologists, and potentially promote human-centred care and healthcare equity in underdeveloped areas.</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>SkinGPT-4: An Interactive Dermatology Diagnostic System with Visual Large Language Model, Oral. Unlocking the Power of “ChatGPT”, King Abdullah University of Science and Technology, Saudi Arabia</title>
    <link>https://www.joshuachou.ink/unlocking-the-power-of-chatgpt/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://www.joshuachou.ink/unlocking-the-power-of-chatgpt/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p></p>
<p></p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
